foodrepublic.com 2014-02-13

# Privacy Policy | Food Republic

FoodRepublic has created this Privacy Policy to inform you about the principles that govern the ways in which we may gather and use information about you. Please know that we respect your desire for privacy. 

This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected through FoodRepublic.com (the “Site”) and does not apply to information collected offline, or to information that you may provide to any third-party sites to which Food Republic may link, except as expressly noted below.

## The Types of Information We Collect

There are two kinds of information that Food Republic can obtain about you: "Anonymous Information" and "Personally Identifiable Information."

"Anonymous Information" consists of non-personally-identifiable data, such as your Internet Protocol ("IP") address or domain, or information about your usage of Food Republic that is used for administrative purposes only. For example, an IP address is a unique string of numbers that is assigned to your computer by your Internet Service Provider. Web servers automatically identify your computer by its IP address. We may collect our users' IP addresses for such purposes as to help diagnose problems with our servers and to report aggregate information to our advertisers, corporate affiliates and consultants, and to third parties that perform particular services on our behalf.

We may also use the information linked to IP addresses to ban users who violate our Terms and Conditions of Use.

"Personally Identifiable Information" is any information that personally identifies you, such as your name, street address, email address, or telephone number. We may collect such information if and when, for example, you enter a contest, sign up for our newsletters or participate in other interactive online activities such as forums via FoodRepublic.com. Such information allows our systems to recognize your Internet browser, and thus to provide you with personalized advertisements and content.

Once you submit your Personally Identifiable Information to us via FoodRepublic.com, we may maintain it in our electronic files; if we do so, you will have the opportunity to correct, amend or delete the Personally Identifiable Information about you that is kept in our files on subsequent visits to the Site.

In most cases, when we collect Personally Identifiable Information from you, we will also afford you the choice to “opt in” to receive email or other digital communications from us and/or our business partners. If you decide to opt in, we may share your Personally Identifiable Information with these business partners so that they may communicate with you directly. We may also disclose such information to strategic or market research consultants whose services we may from time to time engage.

We may also disclose Personally Identifiable Information to others if you otherwise authorize us to do so, if we are required to do so by law or if we in good faith believe that such action is necessary to (a) comply with the law or with legal process; (b) protect and defend our rights and property, including our intellectual property; (c) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of the Site; or (d) protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public. Please note that we may not provide you with notice prior to disclosure in such cases.

Finally, we may provide Personally Identifiable Information to third-party service providers such as credit-card processing companies and businesses that facilitate email newsletter delivery. In providing such services for us, these companies may not retain, share, store or use Personally Identifiable Information for any secondary purposes.

In all events, however, you may be assured that we will only use your information as permitted by law.

## Use of Cookies

FoodRepublic.com uses “cookies" – data that is transferred from FoodRepublic.com to your computer’s hard drive for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies, among other purposes, to deliver content that is specific to your interests. In addition, we will be partnering with one or more third parties that will use cookies to enable them to identify you. One example of such a partnership is our arrangement with a service called Disqus, which will operate the “commenting” system on our Site. Disqus has its own privacy policy, which is accessible at <http://docs.disqus.com/kb/terms-and-policies>.

Some of the advertisements appearing on Food Republic may be delivered by a third-party ad network. In the course of serving advertisements, these ad networks may place or recognize a unique cookie in your browser's cache, and may use Anonymous Information (including the date and time during which an ad was displayed, as well as information about the content of the ad and your IP address, as well as information about your visits to FoodRepublic.com and other Web sites) in order to enable us to provide advertisements about goods and services of likely interest to you and to collect statistical information. If you would like to “opt out” of having a unique cookie placed on your hard drive by our ad networks, please [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

The use of advertising cookies is standard in the Internet industry. Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. If you prefer, you can set yours to refuse cookies or to alert you when cookies are being sent. However, it is possible that some parts of the Site, such as the shopping area, will not function properly if you do so.

The ads appearing on this web site are delivered to you by Google Ad Manager. Information about your visits to this site, such as number of times you have viewed an ad, is aggregated and used to serve ads to you. For more information on Google’s privacy policy, please [click here](http://www.google.com/intl/en/privacy/privacy-policy.html).

## Disclosure of Information through Business Transfers

As we continue to develop our business, we may buy, merge or partner with other companies or businesses, and in so doing, acquire customer information. In such transactions, user information may be among the transferred assets. Similarly, in the event that a portion or all of Food Republic’s assets are sold or transferred to a third party, customer information (including your email address) would likely be one of the transferred business assets.

## Third-Party Web Sites

Food Republic contains links to third-party Web sites that we do not own or control. We are not and cannot be responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such third-party Web sites. The fact that Food Republic may link to another Web site does not imply or express an approval or endorsement of the linked Web site by us, or of any of the content, opinions, products or services provided via these Web sites. Even if an affiliation exists between Food Republic and a particular third-party Web site, we cannot exercise control over such a linked site. Each linked site independently maintains its own privacy and data collection policies and procedures. If you visit a third-party Web site via a link from one of our Sites, we strongly encourage you to consult that Web site's privacy policy before providing any personal information via that site.

We do not provide your Personally Identifiable Information to the third-party Web sites to which our Site may be linked.

## Public Comments and Forums

Food Republic may make such resources as online message and commentary boards, forums, blogs and personal profile pages available to users. Please remember that any such information that you may choose to provide in these areas becomes the property of Food Republic in accordance with our Terms and Conditions, and we may use such information in any way that we see fit. Such information also becomes accessible to the public. Consequently, you should exercise caution when you disclose your personal information via these areas of our Site, or upload material of any kind to the Site.

## Security

Food Republic has put in place reasonable security measures to guard against the loss, misuse or alteration of the information under our control. The security of the information communicated by or to us over the Internet is of utmost concern to us. Please be aware, however, that no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be completely secure. In particular, your email, like most unencrypted Internet communications, may potentially be accessed and viewed by other Internet users, without your knowledge and permission, while in transit to us. For that reason, and to protect your privacy to the greatest extent possible, please do not use email to communicate information to us that you consider confidential. While we strive to protect your personal information, Food Republic cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us. Once we receive your transmission, we will use reasonable efforts to ensure its security on our internal systems. Depending on the nature of the inquiry, your communication may be discarded or archived.

## Policy Regarding Minors

Children should always ask parents before providing any personal information online. No information should be submitted to or posted on Food Republic by any minor (a person under 18 years of age) without the consent of a parent or guardian. Unless otherwise disclosed during collection, we do not knowingly provide any Personally Identifiable Information about minors, regardless of its source, nor is this information knowingly used by Food Republic for any marketing or promotional purposes. Minors are not eligible to participate in contests.

Food Republic abides by the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act. In the event that we learn that we have collected information from any child under the age of 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete this information from our database as quickly as reasonably possible. If you believe that our Site has collected any information about anyone under 13, please contact the Food Republic Site Administrator via postal mail, fax or email, using the contact information given at the end of this Privacy Policy.

## Limitation of Liability

FOOD REPUBLIC PROVIDES THE INFORMATION, SERVICES AND PRODUCTS ON THIS WEB SITES "AS IS" WITHOUT WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND. BY USING THIS SITE, YOU AGREE THAT FOOD REPUBLIC SHALL NOT BE LEGALLY RESPONSIBLE LIABLE FOR ANY CONTENT FOUND ON OUR FORUMS; THAT ANY DOWNLOADING OF MATERIALS FOUND ON OR THROUGH FOOD REPUBLIC FORUMS IS DONE AT YOUR OWN RISK; AND THAT FOOD REPUBLIC IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR UNSOLICITED COMMUNICATIONS THAT MAY ARISE FROM YOUR POSTINGS. FOOD REPUBLIC SHALL NOT BE RESPONSIBLE OR LIABLE IN ANY MANNER FOR THE ACTS OF ANY THIRD PARTY, INCLUDING WITOUT LIMITATION, ANY THIRD PARTY AD NETWORK.

## Consent and Modifications to this Privacy Policy

FoodRepublic.com is controlled, operated and administered entirely within the United States. By using Food Republic and/or participating in any of its online resources and activities, you signify your agreement to the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with the principles set forth in this Privacy Policy, please do not disclose any personal information through our Site. We may modify this Privacy Policy at any time, at our sole discretion, and any such modifications become effective upon being posted on this Site. You are responsible for reviewing this Privacy Policy periodically to ensure that you are made aware of any changes to it.

## Contacting Food Republic

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy you may contact us at:

Site Administrator  
Food Republic  
876 6th Avenue  
19th Floor  
New York NY 10001  
[Click here to contact us](mailto:administrator@foodrepublic.com).

This Privacy Policy is effective as of March 1, 2011.
